<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-19T20:07:17-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Idyl Work</title><subtitle>Doing the work to make the idyl possible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Less is less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Less is less" /><published>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html">&lt;p&gt;Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of the aphorism that &lt;em&gt;less is more&lt;/em&gt;. After a year of more disease, stress, worry, failing systems, and existential crises, I’ve had so much more. I also replaced many of the things that I lost with more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More video calls and social media replaced lost time with friends and family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More endless scroll on the internet replaced lost peace of mind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More sitting has replaced lost physical movement and travel
To not be too gloomy, yes, I’ve gotten more good things as well: more connection with friends who live in other places, more solo hobbies, and more time not commuting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the potential for swapping A for B, today the balance doesn’t feel right. Over the past year, so much changed and was lost. I filled the vacuum in with things that damped the stress and anxiety. The protection is now constraining me, cutting me off from moving forward.
I’m going to prune what is no longer serving me and replacing it with less to create space for… whatever happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a paper called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03380-y&quot;&gt;People systematically overlook subtractive changes&lt;/a&gt;, Leidy Klotz writes about the default attractive nature of addition. He posits that not only might addition be incrementally easier for our brains to process, also “Numerical concepts of ‘more’ and ‘higher’ may map to evaluative concepts of ‘positive’ and ‘better …” and subtraction is a finite process: at some point, you end up with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet addition can’t solve many of the challenges that we are facing today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many meeting during the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much bureaucracy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much time in front of screens (computers or TVs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many commitments to connect with your family or friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, I took part in a socially distanced autocross gathering. Autocross consists of timed driving on a closed course that is short (1-2 kilometers) and it emphasizes car handling over speed, courtesy of delightful twists and turns. While the speeds are slow for autosports, a single pass takes less than a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my 3rd time ever autocrossing and I’m new to the world of technical driving. It is physically difficult, mentally demanding, and technically challenging to hustle a car around a tiny course laid out in cones on a parking lot. That morning I was waiting for my next lap thinking about everything that I had to hurry to improve on a tricky corner. &lt;em&gt;I needed to downshift without losing too much speed, enter on the right, keep the correct throttle position, accelerate out of the turn, exit in a straight line, and finally speed up hard into the next sweeping turn.&lt;/em&gt; Everything about this felt rushed. My hands and feet weren’t in the right place. I was turning in too early, braking too late. I was making it feel hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized I was assuming I wouldn’t be able to do everything that I needed to do, essentially preparing to fail by planning to fail. My approach to that corner assumed I wasn’t fast enough, didn’t have the skills to shift quickly, and wasn’t consistent enough to drive a good line. So I asked myself, &lt;strong&gt;What would happen if I had enough time to do everything to make this corner perfect?&lt;/strong&gt; And with that question in my head, I drove a faster lap than my prior best. The lap also felt easier: I wasn’t rushing into my setup, so I got to the correct place; I gave myself more time to downshift well, so I had more speed when I wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear that I am still very much a beginner in autocross, but by letting go of the need to “do more, faster” I made space to do better. I let myself use the skills and experience that I had, rather than feeling the need to do more of something that I didn’t understand. I had made even more improvements, and I was having even more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using that question from autocross to help me envision a fresh way of existing with less pressure, less assuming failure, and less focus solely on mitigating the worst potential outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to reading Leidy Klotz’s book that I’m waiting to get from the library: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/subtract-the-untapped-science-of-less/9781250249869&quot;&gt;Subtract: The untapped science of less&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><summary type="html">Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thank you and good bye, old habits</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thank you and good bye, old habits" /><published>2021-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits.html">&lt;p&gt;Can we do more to celebrate changing old habits, behaviors, or legacy strategies we no longer need as an element of recognizing lifelong growth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/immunity-to-change-how-to-overcome-it-and-unlock-potential-in-yourself-and-your-organization/9781422117361&quot;&gt;Immunity to Change&lt;/a&gt;, the authors describe the importance of recognizing how we have navigated life using skills that we might now want to change. These practices sustained us through difficulties and helped us achieve enough balance in our life that we now can see a life without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blame or disappointment may enable short-term progress, does starting from a place of avoidance and shame build the foundation for the best possible outcomes? Instead, can we recognize and validate what we want to change and build on our strength to reach this point? Maybe moving past what isn’t working for us would be easier if it isn’t a failure but rather a sign of progress? By acknowledging that we are constantly adapting and growing, these changes become milestones along a lifelong journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for all the prior help, old habits. I can’t wait to move beyond you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><category term="change" /><summary type="html">Can we do more to celebrate changing old habits, behaviors, or legacy strategies we no longer need as an element of recognizing lifelong growth?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on the kick-off</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on the kick-off" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kick-off of OLCC has encouraged me to slow down and consider some Big Questions that felt like a breath of fresh air like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do my actions versus my words demonstrate my commitments?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I gain more insight into whether I am living into my definition of a life that combines fulfillment, balance, and process in the best measure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the kick-off, chapter from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/co-active-coaching-changing-business-transforming-lives-9781857885675/9781857885675&quot;&gt;Co-Active Coaching: Changing Business, Transforming Lives&lt;/a&gt; included a challenge to do the radical act of living a fulfilling life, which inspired more questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is my definition of a fulfilling life?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I intentionally design my coaching interactions (and all work) to create and enable participants’ fulfillment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If it is the role of coaches “to be clear about what a fulfilling work-life looks like and be willing to take a stand for it …,” can I coach others while also analyzing this question myself? &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 167)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also felt energized by the encouragement to “[d]esign your coaching offering so that it resonates with your values and provides balance in your own life.” &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 169)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to attain, or get closer to, a truly fulfilling life feels so essential and somewhat impossible. But I’m wondering: &lt;em&gt;Will I ever feel ready to work with others on these significant goals?&lt;/em&gt; To get there, I’ll try to channel the “brave space” created by OLCC to remember that at this moment, bravery is required because “learning necessarily involves not merely risk, but the pain of giving up a former condition in favor of a new way of seeing things.” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gvsu.edu/cms4/asset/843249C9-B1E5-BD47-A25EDBC68363B726/from-safe-spaces-to-brave-spaces.pdf&quot;&gt;Robert Boostrom, quoted here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent more than a year of sheltering in place, working from home full time, and leaving only for essential purposes. This year has presented me with opportunities and challenges that I’ve experienced but not reflected on in a larger context of their impact on me. The kick-off session reminded me that I could create space for this reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="learning" /><category term="coaching" /><category term="questions" /><summary type="html">Wow, what a beginning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting" /><published>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</published><updated>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is a test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this post is a starting point for my work on Northwestern’s Organizational and Leadership Coaching Certificate. I’m pursuing it as part of a Master’s of Science in Learning and Organizational Change. That’s a mouthful, I know. I’ll add more detail in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m testing systems and building my own website to remind myself that this is a form of creative expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve pulled the bandaid off now, let’s see where we go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="msloc" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">This post is a test.</summary></entry></feed>