<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-12T12:04:39-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">idyl work</title><subtitle>Doing the work to make the idyl possible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Categories of question</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/categories-of-questions" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Categories of question" /><published>2021-08-09T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-09T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/categories-of-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/categories-of-questions">&lt;p&gt;I’m a curious person and I love a good question. This leads me to ponder questions in the back of my mind while running or to save good questions from other. In my next run, I’ll be thinking about this quote from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/humble-inquiry-second/9781523092642/&quot;&gt;2nd edition of Humble Inquiry&lt;/a&gt;, where Edgar Schein notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Keeping up with the content of accelerating change is really hard. … Yet trying to keep up with the content of accelerating change may actually be less important than keeping up with the context of accelerating change. There is a real difference between the content question “What changed?” and the context question “What is going on?” or “Why is this happening?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next weeks, I’ll be asking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do my questions in different arenas, relationships, and topics focus on context or content?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When does a context questions feel more natural?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What questions are impactful for particular clients?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">I’m a curious person and I love a good question. This leads me to ponder questions in the back of my mind while running or to save good questions from other. In my next run, I’ll be thinking about this quote from the 2nd edition of Humble Inquiry, where Edgar Schein notes:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is presence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is presence" /><published>2021-08-04T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-04T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence.html">&lt;p&gt;And how can I bring presence to the coaching experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presence is defined by the dictionary as: &lt;em&gt;“the state or fact of existing, occurring, or being present in a place or thing.”&lt;/em&gt; Alternatively the &lt;a href=&quot;https://coachingfederation.org/core-competencies&quot;&gt;International Coaching Federation&lt;/a&gt; defines presence as &lt;em&gt;“Ability to be fully conscious and create spontaneous relationship with the client, employing a style that is open, flexible and confident.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presence feels fully distinct from “being present” which is something that is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current thoughts are that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence is a shared experience that we can experience if we create the space and opportunity to connect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence can be given by one person to another&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence creates the possibility to discover by allowing the unexpected to happen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><summary type="html">And how can I bring presence to the coaching experience?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Considering resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Considering resistance" /><published>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html">&lt;p&gt;Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most common form of resistance takes the form of continuously looking for more information. This often takes the form of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seeking more details&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;searching for the perfect solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;believing that resolution can be discovered through additional research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This perpetual hunt for details and information stops me from applying what I already know, which is often enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resistance occurs from time to time during coaching as clients work towards goals. We can move through resistance together by recognizing it is happening, making a plan to engage with the resistance, and creating space for the client to address it with courage and without judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching with consulting models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/coaching-with-consulting-models" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching with consulting models" /><published>2021-06-30T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/process-consulting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/coaching-with-consulting-models">&lt;p&gt;dgar Schein describes 3 models of working with clients in his article “What is process consultation?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Process Consultation Model, coach and client will work together 50/50 from initial discovery and diagnosis. Instead of solving problems for the client, the process consultant teaches the client how to solve their own problems and supports them through the process. Schein notes that “expertise is less relevant than… the skills of involving the client in self-diagnosis and helping… find a remedy that fits his particular situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schein notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Process Consultation is the creation of a relationship with the client that &lt;em&gt;permits the client to perceive, understand, and act&lt;/em&gt; on the process events that occur in the client’s internal and external environment in order to improve the situation as defined by the client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Expertise Model emphasizes specialized knowledge and applying highly technical skills to a client who has already appropriately diagnosed a problem (Schein, 1999, p 7). The expert model allows a consultant to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show targeted specialization in a narrow, highly specific field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on providing a specific solution without participating in diagnosis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assess the outcome effectively for the client using their expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doctor-Patient model envisions a role that assesses the situation to create a diagnosis which is shared with the patient/client to select the most appropriate treatment plan (Schein, 1999, p 11). The consultant may administer the prescribed response, but will certainly provide a highly detailed presentation of findings and recommendations to show their value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My questions are: How can I balance these different models to best support my clients? How will I get feedback about what is working or not? How can I continuously increase my skills across these models to be optimally effective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schein, E. H. (1999). What is process consultation? Process consultation revisited: Building the helping relationship (pp. 3-29). Reading, PA: Addison-Wesley.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">dgar Schein describes 3 models of working with clients in his article “What is process consultation?”</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is the why?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/06/15/what-is-the-why.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is the why?" /><published>2021-06-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-06-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/06/15/what-is-the-why</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/06/15/what-is-the-why.html">&lt;p&gt;Many conversations start with an initial and maybe implicit question: why are we talking? Reasons might be aligned or conflicting between the parties, but each person has an idea of the &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt; for the conversation. As a curiosity-driven person, I can find a why for almost any exploration 🍭&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Especially during the intake process for coaching, I want to be guided by the client’s interest, needs, pacing, and questions. Does this mean that my curiosity will derail a client’s sense of ownership over our conversation? How can I avoid power struggles and not direct conversations to answer questions I find fascinating, but that might not serve my clients?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want to find ways to channel my curiosity to serve the client’s discovery process while being authentic and fully present … right now this feels like no small task!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;intake, making space for questioning &amp;amp; discovery&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">Many conversations start with an initial and maybe implicit question: why are we talking? Reasons might be aligned or conflicting between the parties, but each person has an idea of the why for the conversation. As a curiosity-driven person, I can find a why for almost any exploration 🍭</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quick thoughts on authenticity at work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quick thoughts on authenticity at work" /><published>2021-05-23T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-23T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work.html">&lt;p&gt;The value of authenticity has become common knowledge in leadership and management literature. On an individual level, authenticity reduces dissonance and may increase well-being. Essentially authenticity makes it easier to be at work. From an organizational perspective, an employee who intentionally conforms rather than acting authentically must direct additional attention and energy to managing their relationships and interactions at work. Conforming also minimizes the perspectives and information that could improve decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves us all to evaluate how much of ourselves to bring to any situation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/how_to_be_more_authentic_at_work&quot;&gt;Patricia Faison Hewlin&lt;/a&gt; writes: “Authenticity is not really about exuding everything and baring your soul all the time. It’s about identifying what’s important to you and determining how much you can integrate those values into your work life or other areas, so that you can experience life satisfaction, feel engaged, and make a positive contribution to work and society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this framing, authenticity can be a concept that empowers you by identifying your values and core beliefs. With this self-knowledge, you can make intentional decisions about what authenticity means for you at the moment. It also prepares you if values conflicts arise; self-knowledge can improve clarity about which of your values was affected by a particular experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations can take explicit steps that enable individuals to exist more authentically at work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace different experiences, opinions, and perspectives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight positive outcomes that do not require agreement and consensus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it safe for people to disagree, make mistakes, and fail when they learn from the process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create time for reflection and learning at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every individual and organization will have different approaches to authenticity. Regardless of the starting point, it is possible to learn new skills and develop strategies to align your experience of authenticity with your current and future needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="quick" /><summary type="html">The value of authenticity has become common knowledge in leadership and management literature. On an individual level, authenticity reduces dissonance and may increase well-being. Essentially authenticity makes it easier to be at work. From an organizational perspective, an employee who intentionally conforms rather than acting authentically must direct additional attention and energy to managing their relationships and interactions at work. Conforming also minimizes the perspectives and information that could improve decision making.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Threat vs reward: what is motivating this action?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Threat vs reward: what is motivating this action?" /><published>2021-05-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates.html">&lt;p&gt;Threat &amp;amp; reward are two poles of a spectrum that individuals and organizations experience. These terms encompass our responses to the full spectrum of experiences from negative to positive. Both threat and reward can be very motivational, but the experience and long term result are not equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Threat&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Reward&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Individual&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- A meeting with a stakeholder throws the future of a multi-year project into doubt - A re-org, the goals and scope of a team have reduced the possibility of growth&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- Receiving meaningful recognition for contributing to a project - Experiencing an energizing flow state&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- New competition threatens what used to be a stable source of revenue - Rapid growth leads to challenges in organizational effectiveness and employee engagement&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- Delivering value for clients in an impactful manner - Overcoming a hardship to unlock new potential&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a quick heuristic you can use when considering a change or making a plan: What is motivating this change? 
If you are trying to minimize risk, mitigate negative outcomes, and manage uncertainty you are probably acting on a threat response.
If you are maximizing the chance for success, combining multiple perspectives into a complex solution, or embracing change as a new opportunity, then you are probably acting on a reward-based model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This topic relates to David Rock’s SCARF model, which I’ll dig into more in the future. For more on SCARF, you can read his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306&quot;&gt;Managing with the brain in mind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="msloc" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="motivation" /><summary type="html">Threat &amp;amp; reward are two poles of a spectrum that individuals and organizations experience. These terms encompass our responses to the full spectrum of experiences from negative to positive. Both threat and reward can be very motivational, but the experience and long term result are not equal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rediscovering joys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rediscovering joys" /><published>2021-05-07T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can we get alienated from our unique definitions of happiness and fulfillment? When we do, how do we discover a new version that is authentically ours?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days, I have forgotten the experience of the alive version of myself after more than a year of stress, anticipation, and worry. To be honest, I worked with these factors before COVID-19 made these challenges visible and gave so many of us a shared platform to talk about missing pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Seligman describes happiness as a construct of 3 types of wellbeing: &lt;em&gt;pleasure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;engagement&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;. As described in 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6688745/#S1title&quot;&gt;Unpacking grit: Motivational correlates of perseverance and passion for long-term goals&lt;/a&gt; (2014 work done in part by Angela Duckworth), each person balances these factors and their interest in &lt;em&gt;flow&lt;/em&gt;. Each factor has different rewards and requires different activities to achieve it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flow-seekers engage concentration that may overcome self-awareness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pleasure-seekers can embrace novelty, which can be instantly pleasurable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meaning-seekers invest time and effort to work towards their definition of a greater good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we take this list of abstract concepts and make it relevant to ourselves? This practice is working for me right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noticing when something is working and what isn’t. Write it down so I can focus on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each thing, dig deeper into relevant factors: What are you getting? What’s missing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-example-from-my-life&quot;&gt;An example from my life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making this website brings me a surprising amount of happiness, something I’ve recently realized. I’m using making intentionally, because IdylWork is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a static site I’m building with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; with every change and struggle visible at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laureli/laureli.github.io&quot;&gt;https://github.com/laureli/laureli.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;made with open source &amp;amp; publicly available resources like my theme &lt;a href=&quot;https://fongandrew.github.io/hydeout/&quot;&gt;Hydeout&lt;/a&gt; and this code that &lt;a href=&quot;https://jdvp.me/articles/Google-Forms-Jekyll-Comments&quot;&gt;uses google docs to display comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;deeply&lt;/em&gt; love:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The only money I spent was registering my domain with &lt;a href=&quot;https://gandi.net&quot;&gt;Gandi.net&lt;/a&gt;, a company supporting protections for free speech, privacy, and data security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;NO ADS&lt;/em&gt;. The only analytics (user data collection) on this page are mine and they’re here to ensure uptime &amp;amp; reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t have to use Wordpress, Wix, Medium or whatever other platform that’s monetize me, my content, and readers. (This is SO satisfying.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In table form, this might look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Pleasure&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Engagement&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Flow&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Creating content and picking the tools I want is incredibly satisfying&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Solving the infinite problems that you find when building with multiple open-source tools has taken research and experiments&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Building skills I can use to help other people&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Writing (very basic) code has been difficult but surprisingly rewarding and flow-y&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Having an additional reason to read more&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Discovering an authentic voice for this site&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Refining my writing skills so that I can communicate effectively&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Self expression: Writing content and having control over this entire site&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Spending money only with services that have aligned values&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Learning &amp;amp; relearning skills that I’ve not touched for years: ruby, git, etc&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Not using platforms that I disagree with&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I could research and optimize all day, everyday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Getting a good deal ;)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I dug deeper into the components of happiness, I remembered more about why these things contribute to my happiness and satisfaction. It also helps me to spot more opportunities to try on and experiment with potential pathways to happiness and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try it, let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="eudaimonia" /><summary type="html">Can we get alienated from our unique definitions of happiness and fulfillment? When we do, how do we discover a new version that is authentically ours?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reframing failure</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reframing failure" /><published>2021-04-25T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-25T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure.html">&lt;p&gt;Asking “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” seems positive, but consider some possible reframes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you do if failure wasn’t a defeat, bad, or a sign of inability?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What could you learn if failures gave you additional information?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if a failure wasn’t the last step, but an intermediary step on a longer journey?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who never quite believe that we can’t fail, “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” the belief that failure has to be avoided. It encourages us to reject failure by not even considering the possibility and sets us up to face risks we haven’t addressed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the negativity may require adopting a fresh approach to failure. To avoid cliched statistics, let’s talk about &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;failure rates&lt;/code&gt;. A failure rate is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/failure-rate&quot;&gt;the expected number of times that a system or item will fail in a period of time&lt;/a&gt;. The information about any failure (or lack thereof) contributes to the next iteration of that system or item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we reframe failure, some relevant questions become: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What can I learn from this failure to improve outcomes the next time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there failures that I can expect and plan to learn from in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="general" /><category term="test" /><summary type="html">Asking “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” seems positive, but consider some possible reframes:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Less is less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Less is less" /><published>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html">&lt;p&gt;Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of the aphorism that &lt;em&gt;less is more&lt;/em&gt;. After a year of more disease, stress, worry, failing systems, and existential crises, I’ve had so much more. I also replaced many of the things that I lost with more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More video calls and social media replaced lost time with friends and family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More endless scroll on the internet replaced lost peace of mind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More sitting has replaced lost physical movement and travel
To not be too gloomy, yes, I’ve gotten more good things as well: more connection with friends who live in other places, more solo hobbies, and more time not commuting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the potential for swapping A for B, today the balance doesn’t feel right. Over the past year, so much changed and was lost. I filled the vacuum in with things that damped the stress and anxiety. The protection is now constraining me, cutting me off from moving forward.
I’m going to prune what is no longer serving me and replacing it with less to create space for… whatever happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a paper called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03380-y&quot;&gt;People systematically overlook subtractive changes&lt;/a&gt;, Leidy Klotz writes about the default attractive nature of addition. He posits that not only might addition be incrementally easier for our brains to process, also “Numerical concepts of ‘more’ and ‘higher’ may map to evaluative concepts of ‘positive’ and ‘better …” and subtraction is a finite process: at some point, you end up with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet addition can’t solve many of the challenges that we are facing today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many meeting during the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much bureaucracy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much time in front of screens (computers or TVs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many commitments to connect with your family or friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, I took part in a socially distanced autocross gathering. Autocross consists of timed driving on a closed course that is short (1-2 kilometers) and it emphasizes car handling over speed, courtesy of delightful twists and turns. While the speeds are slow for autosports, a single pass takes less than a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my 3rd time ever autocrossing and I’m new to the world of technical driving. It is physically difficult, mentally demanding, and technically challenging to hustle a car around a tiny course laid out in cones on a parking lot. That morning I was waiting for my next lap thinking about everything that I had to hurry to improve on a tricky corner. &lt;em&gt;I needed to downshift without losing too much speed, enter on the right, keep the correct throttle position, accelerate out of the turn, exit in a straight line, and finally speed up hard into the next sweeping turn.&lt;/em&gt; Everything about this felt rushed. My hands and feet weren’t in the right place. I was turning in too early, braking too late. I was making it feel hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized I was assuming I wouldn’t be able to do everything that I needed to do, essentially preparing to fail by planning to fail. My approach to that corner assumed I wasn’t fast enough, didn’t have the skills to shift quickly, and wasn’t consistent enough to drive a good line. So I asked myself, &lt;strong&gt;What would happen if I had enough time to do everything to make this corner perfect?&lt;/strong&gt; And with that question in my head, I drove a faster lap than my prior best. The lap also felt easier: I wasn’t rushing into my setup, so I got to the correct place; I gave myself more time to downshift well, so I had more speed when I wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear that I am still very much a beginner in autocross, but by letting go of the need to “do more, faster” I made space to do better. I let myself use the skills and experience that I had, rather than feeling the need to do more of something that I didn’t understand. I had made even more improvements, and I was having even more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using that question from autocross to help me envision a fresh way of existing with less pressure, less assuming failure, and less focus solely on mitigating the worst potential outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to reading Leidy Klotz’s book that I’m waiting to get from the library: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/subtract-the-untapped-science-of-less/9781250249869&quot;&gt;Subtract: The untapped science of less&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><summary type="html">Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?</summary></entry></feed>