<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-04-11T22:21:18-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Idyl Work</title><subtitle>Doing the work to make the idyl possible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on the kick-off</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on the kick-off" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kick-off of OLCC has encouraged me to slow down and consider some Big Questions that felt like a breath of fresh air like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do my actions versus my words demonstrate my commitments?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I gain more insight into whether I am living into my definition of a life that combines fulfillment, balance, and process in the best measure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the kick-off, chapter from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/co-active-coaching-changing-business-transforming-lives-9781857885675/9781857885675&quot;&gt;Co-Active Coaching: Changing Business, Transforming Lives&lt;/a&gt; included a challenge to do the radical act of living a fulfilling life, which inspired more questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is my definition of a fulfilling life?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I intentionally design my coaching interactions (and all work) to create and enable participants’ fulfillment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If it is the role of coaches “to be clear about what a fulfilling work-life looks like and be willing to take a stand for it …,” can I coach others while also analyzing this question myself? &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 167)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also felt energized by the encouragement to “[d]esign your coaching offering so that it resonates with your values and provides balance in your own life.” &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 169)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to attain, or get closer to, a truly fulfilling life feels so essential and somewhat impossible. But I’m wondering: &lt;em&gt;Will I ever feel ready to work with others on these significant goals?&lt;/em&gt; To get there, I’ll try to channel the “brave space” created by OLCC to remember that at this moment, bravery is required because “learning necessarily involves not merely risk, but the pain of giving up a former condition in favor of a new way of seeing things.” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gvsu.edu/cms4/asset/843249C9-B1E5-BD47-A25EDBC68363B726/from-safe-spaces-to-brave-spaces.pdf&quot;&gt;Robert Boostrom, quoted here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent more than a year of sheltering in place, working from home full time, and leaving only for essential purposes. This year has presented me with opportunities and challenges that I’ve experienced but not reflected on in a larger context of their impact on me. The kick-off session reminded me that I could create space for this reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="learning" /><category term="coaching" /><category term="questions" /><summary type="html">Wow, what a beginning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting" /><published>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</published><updated>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is a test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this post is a starting point for my work on Northwestern’s Organizational and Leadership Coaching Certificate. I’m pursuing it as part of a Master’s of Science in Learning and Organizational Change. That’s a mouthful, I know. I’ll add more detail in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m testing systems and building my own website to remind myself that this is a form of creative expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve pulled the bandaid off now, let’s see where we go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="msloc" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">This post is a test.</summary></entry></feed>