<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-07-31T15:01:38-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">idyl work</title><subtitle>Doing the work to make the idyl possible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Considering resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Considering resistance" /><published>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html">&lt;p&gt;Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most common form of resistance takes the form of continuously looking for more information. This often takes the form of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seeking more details&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;searching for the perfect solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;believing that resolution can be discovered through additional research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This perpetual hunt for details and information stops me from applying what I already know, which is often enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resistance occurs from time to time during coaching as clients work towards goals. We can move through resistance together by recognizing it is happening, making a plan to engage with the resistance, and creating space for the client to address it with courage and without judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Quick thoughts on authenticity at work</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Quick thoughts on authenticity at work" /><published>2021-05-23T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-23T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/23/quick-thoughts-on-authenticity-at-work.html">&lt;p&gt;The value of authenticity has become common knowledge in leadership and management literature. On an individual level, authenticity reduces dissonance and may increase well-being. Essentially authenticity makes it easier to be at work. From an organizational perspective, an employee who intentionally conforms rather than acting authentically must direct additional attention and energy to managing their relationships and interactions at work. Conforming also minimizes the perspectives and information that could improve decision making.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This leaves us all to evaluate how much of ourselves to bring to any situation. &lt;a href=&quot;https://greatergood.berkeley.edu/article/item/how_to_be_more_authentic_at_work&quot;&gt;Patricia Faison Hewlin&lt;/a&gt; writes: “Authenticity is not really about exuding everything and baring your soul all the time. It’s about identifying what’s important to you and determining how much you can integrate those values into your work life or other areas, so that you can experience life satisfaction, feel engaged, and make a positive contribution to work and society.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this framing, authenticity can be a concept that empowers you by identifying your values and core beliefs. With this self-knowledge, you can make intentional decisions about what authenticity means for you at the moment. It also prepares you if values conflicts arise; self-knowledge can improve clarity about which of your values was affected by a particular experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Organizations can take explicit steps that enable individuals to exist more authentically at work:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Embrace different experiences, opinions, and perspectives.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Highlight positive outcomes that do not require agreement and consensus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make it safe for people to disagree, make mistakes, and fail when they learn from the process.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Create time for reflection and learning at work.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every individual and organization will have different approaches to authenticity. Regardless of the starting point, it is possible to learn new skills and develop strategies to align your experience of authenticity with your current and future needs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="quick" /><summary type="html">The value of authenticity has become common knowledge in leadership and management literature. On an individual level, authenticity reduces dissonance and may increase well-being. Essentially authenticity makes it easier to be at work. From an organizational perspective, an employee who intentionally conforms rather than acting authentically must direct additional attention and energy to managing their relationships and interactions at work. Conforming also minimizes the perspectives and information that could improve decision making.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Threat vs reward: what is motivating this action?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Threat vs reward: what is motivating this action?" /><published>2021-05-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/05/15/threat-vs-reward-what-motivates.html">&lt;p&gt;Threat &amp;amp; reward are two poles of a spectrum that individuals and organizations experience. These terms encompass our responses to the full spectrum of experiences from negative to positive. Both threat and reward can be very motivational, but the experience and long term result are not equal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt; &lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Threat&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Reward&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Individual&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- A meeting with a stakeholder throws the future of a multi-year project into doubt - A re-org, the goals and scope of a team have reduced the possibility of growth&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- Receiving meaningful recognition for contributing to a project - Experiencing an energizing flow state&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Organization&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- New competition threatens what used to be a stable source of revenue - Rapid growth leads to challenges in organizational effectiveness and employee engagement&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;- Delivering value for clients in an impactful manner - Overcoming a hardship to unlock new potential&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This gives us a quick heuristic you can use when considering a change or making a plan: What is motivating this change? 
If you are trying to minimize risk, mitigate negative outcomes, and manage uncertainty you are probably acting on a threat response.
If you are maximizing the chance for success, combining multiple perspectives into a complex solution, or embracing change as a new opportunity, then you are probably acting on a reward-based model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This topic relates to David Rock’s SCARF model, which I’ll dig into more in the future. For more on SCARF, you can read his article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.strategy-business.com/article/09306&quot;&gt;Managing with the brain in mind&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="msloc" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="motivation" /><summary type="html">Threat &amp;amp; reward are two poles of a spectrum that individuals and organizations experience. These terms encompass our responses to the full spectrum of experiences from negative to positive. Both threat and reward can be very motivational, but the experience and long term result are not equal.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Rediscovering joys</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rediscovering joys" /><published>2021-05-07T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/05/07/rediscovering-forgotten-joys.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Can we get alienated from our unique definitions of happiness and fulfillment? When we do, how do we discover a new version that is authentically ours?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some days, I have forgotten the experience of the alive version of myself after more than a year of stress, anticipation, and worry. To be honest, I worked with these factors before COVID-19 made these challenges visible and gave so many of us a shared platform to talk about missing pieces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martin Seligman describes happiness as a construct of 3 types of wellbeing: &lt;em&gt;pleasure&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;engagement&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;meaning&lt;/em&gt;. As described in 
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC6688745/#S1title&quot;&gt;Unpacking grit: Motivational correlates of perseverance and passion for long-term goals&lt;/a&gt; (2014 work done in part by Angela Duckworth), each person balances these factors and their interest in &lt;em&gt;flow&lt;/em&gt;. Each factor has different rewards and requires different activities to achieve it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flow-seekers engage concentration that may overcome self-awareness&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;pleasure-seekers can embrace novelty, which can be instantly pleasurable&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meaning-seekers invest time and effort to work towards their definition of a greater good&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we take this list of abstract concepts and make it relevant to ourselves? This practice is working for me right now:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Noticing when something is working and what isn’t. Write it down so I can focus on it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;For each thing, dig deeper into relevant factors: What are you getting? What’s missing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;an-example-from-my-life&quot;&gt;An example from my life&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Making this website brings me a surprising amount of happiness, something I’ve recently realized. I’m using making intentionally, because IdylWork is:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a static site I’m building with &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; with every change and struggle visible at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/laureli/laureli.github.io&quot;&gt;https://github.com/laureli/laureli.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;made with open source &amp;amp; publicly available resources like my theme &lt;a href=&quot;https://fongandrew.github.io/hydeout/&quot;&gt;Hydeout&lt;/a&gt; and this code that &lt;a href=&quot;https://jdvp.me/articles/Google-Forms-Jekyll-Comments&quot;&gt;uses google docs to display comments&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I &lt;em&gt;deeply&lt;/em&gt; love:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The only money I spent was registering my domain with &lt;a href=&quot;https://gandi.net&quot;&gt;Gandi.net&lt;/a&gt;, a company supporting protections for free speech, privacy, and data security&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are &lt;em&gt;NO ADS&lt;/em&gt;. The only analytics (user data collection) on this page are mine and they’re here to ensure uptime &amp;amp; reliability.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I don’t have to use Wordpress, Wix, Medium or whatever other platform that’s monetize me, my content, and readers. (This is SO satisfying.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In table form, this might look like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Pleasure&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Engagement&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Meaning&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Flow&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Creating content and picking the tools I want is incredibly satisfying&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Solving the infinite problems that you find when building with multiple open-source tools has taken research and experiments&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Building skills I can use to help other people&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Writing (very basic) code has been difficult but surprisingly rewarding and flow-y&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Having an additional reason to read more&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Discovering an authentic voice for this site&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Refining my writing skills so that I can communicate effectively&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Self expression: Writing content and having control over this entire site&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Spending money only with services that have aligned values&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Learning &amp;amp; relearning skills that I’ve not touched for years: ruby, git, etc&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Not using platforms that I disagree with&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;I could research and optimize all day, everyday&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Getting a good deal ;)&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt; &lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I dug deeper into the components of happiness, I remembered more about why these things contribute to my happiness and satisfaction. It also helps me to spot more opportunities to try on and experiment with potential pathways to happiness and fulfillment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you try it, let me know what you think in the comments.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="eudaimonia" /><summary type="html">Can we get alienated from our unique definitions of happiness and fulfillment? When we do, how do we discover a new version that is authentically ours?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reframing failure</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reframing failure" /><published>2021-04-25T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-25T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/olcc/2021/04/25/reframing-failure.html">&lt;p&gt;Asking “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” seems positive, but consider some possible reframes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What would you do if failure wasn’t a defeat, bad, or a sign of inability?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What could you learn if failures gave you additional information?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What if a failure wasn’t the last step, but an intermediary step on a longer journey?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those of us who never quite believe that we can’t fail, “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” the belief that failure has to be avoided. It encourages us to reject failure by not even considering the possibility and sets us up to face risks we haven’t addressed. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Removing the negativity may require adopting a fresh approach to failure. To avoid cliched statistics, let’s talk about &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;failure rates&lt;/code&gt;. A failure rate is &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/topics/engineering/failure-rate&quot;&gt;the expected number of times that a system or item will fail in a period of time&lt;/a&gt;. The information about any failure (or lack thereof) contributes to the next iteration of that system or item.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we reframe failure, some relevant questions become: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What can I learn from this failure to improve outcomes the next time?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are there failures that I can expect and plan to learn from in the future?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="general" /><category term="test" /><summary type="html">Asking “What would you do if you knew you couldn’t fail?” seems positive, but consider some possible reframes:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Less is less</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Less is less" /><published>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/04/18/less-is-less.html">&lt;p&gt;Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m tired of the aphorism that &lt;em&gt;less is more&lt;/em&gt;. After a year of more disease, stress, worry, failing systems, and existential crises, I’ve had so much more. I also replaced many of the things that I lost with more:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More video calls and social media replaced lost time with friends and family&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More endless scroll on the internet replaced lost peace of mind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More sitting has replaced lost physical movement and travel
To not be too gloomy, yes, I’ve gotten more good things as well: more connection with friends who live in other places, more solo hobbies, and more time not commuting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the potential for swapping A for B, today the balance doesn’t feel right. Over the past year, so much changed and was lost. I filled the vacuum in with things that damped the stress and anxiety. The protection is now constraining me, cutting me off from moving forward.
I’m going to prune what is no longer serving me and replacing it with less to create space for… whatever happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a paper called &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41586-021-03380-y&quot;&gt;People systematically overlook subtractive changes&lt;/a&gt;, Leidy Klotz writes about the default attractive nature of addition. He posits that not only might addition be incrementally easier for our brains to process, also “Numerical concepts of ‘more’ and ‘higher’ may map to evaluative concepts of ‘positive’ and ‘better …” and subtraction is a finite process: at some point, you end up with nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet addition can’t solve many of the challenges that we are facing today:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many meeting during the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much bureaucracy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too much time in front of screens (computers or TVs)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Too many commitments to connect with your family or friends&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of last year, I took part in a socially distanced autocross gathering. Autocross consists of timed driving on a closed course that is short (1-2 kilometers) and it emphasizes car handling over speed, courtesy of delightful twists and turns. While the speeds are slow for autosports, a single pass takes less than a minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was my 3rd time ever autocrossing and I’m new to the world of technical driving. It is physically difficult, mentally demanding, and technically challenging to hustle a car around a tiny course laid out in cones on a parking lot. That morning I was waiting for my next lap thinking about everything that I had to hurry to improve on a tricky corner. &lt;em&gt;I needed to downshift without losing too much speed, enter on the right, keep the correct throttle position, accelerate out of the turn, exit in a straight line, and finally speed up hard into the next sweeping turn.&lt;/em&gt; Everything about this felt rushed. My hands and feet weren’t in the right place. I was turning in too early, braking too late. I was making it feel hard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I realized I was assuming I wouldn’t be able to do everything that I needed to do, essentially preparing to fail by planning to fail. My approach to that corner assumed I wasn’t fast enough, didn’t have the skills to shift quickly, and wasn’t consistent enough to drive a good line. So I asked myself, &lt;strong&gt;What would happen if I had enough time to do everything to make this corner perfect?&lt;/strong&gt; And with that question in my head, I drove a faster lap than my prior best. The lap also felt easier: I wasn’t rushing into my setup, so I got to the correct place; I gave myself more time to downshift well, so I had more speed when I wanted it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be clear that I am still very much a beginner in autocross, but by letting go of the need to “do more, faster” I made space to do better. I let myself use the skills and experience that I had, rather than feeling the need to do more of something that I didn’t understand. I had made even more improvements, and I was having even more fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using that question from autocross to help me envision a fresh way of existing with less pressure, less assuming failure, and less focus solely on mitigating the worst potential outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to reading Leidy Klotz’s book that I’m waiting to get from the library: &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/subtract-the-untapped-science-of-less/9781250249869&quot;&gt;Subtract: The untapped science of less&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><summary type="html">Question of the week: Can I rebalance by letting go and having less of that which isn’t helping me?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Goodbye, old habits (i’ll see you later)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Goodbye, old habits (i’ll see you later)" /><published>2021-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-04-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/04/10/thank-you-old-habits.html">&lt;p&gt;Can we do more to celebrate changing old habits, behaviors, or legacy strategies we no longer need as an element of recognizing lifelong growth?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/immunity-to-change-how-to-overcome-it-and-unlock-potential-in-yourself-and-your-organization/9781422117361&quot;&gt;Immunity to Change&lt;/a&gt;, the authors describe the importance of recognizing how we have navigated life using skills that we might now want to change. These practices sustained us through difficulties and helped us achieve enough balance in our life that we now can see a life without them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While blame or disappointment may enable short-term progress, does starting from a place of avoidance and shame build the foundation for the best possible outcomes? Instead, can we recognize and validate what we want to change and build on our strength to reach this point? Maybe moving past what isn’t working for us would be easier if it isn’t a failure but rather a sign of progress? By acknowledging that we are constantly adapting and growing, these changes become milestones along a lifelong journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, thank you for all the prior help, old habits. I can’t wait to move beyond you.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><category term="change" /><summary type="html">Can we do more to celebrate changing old habits, behaviors, or legacy strategies we no longer need as an element of recognizing lifelong growth?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Thoughts on the kick-off</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Thoughts on the kick-off" /><published>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-03-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/olcc/micro-blog/2021/03/25/thoughts-on-kickoff.html">&lt;p&gt;Wow, what a beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The kick-off of OLCC has encouraged me to slow down and consider some Big Questions that felt like a breath of fresh air like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do my actions versus my words demonstrate my commitments?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I gain more insight into whether I am living into my definition of a life that combines fulfillment, balance, and process in the best measure?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the kick-off, chapter from &lt;a href=&quot;https://bookshop.org/books/co-active-coaching-changing-business-transforming-lives-9781857885675/9781857885675&quot;&gt;Co-Active Coaching: Changing Business, Transforming Lives&lt;/a&gt; included a challenge to do the radical act of living a fulfilling life, which inspired more questions:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What is my definition of a fulfilling life?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How can I intentionally design my coaching interactions (and all work) to create and enable participants’ fulfillment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If it is the role of coaches “to be clear about what a fulfilling work-life looks like and be willing to take a stand for it …,” can I coach others while also analyzing this question myself? &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 167)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also felt energized by the encouragement to “[d]esign your coaching offering so that it resonates with your values and provides balance in your own life.” &lt;em&gt;(Co-Active Coaching, p. 169)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The opportunity to attain, or get closer to, a truly fulfilling life feels so essential and somewhat impossible. But I’m wondering: &lt;em&gt;Will I ever feel ready to work with others on these significant goals?&lt;/em&gt; To get there, I’ll try to channel the “brave space” created by OLCC to remember that at this moment, bravery is required because “learning necessarily involves not merely risk, but the pain of giving up a former condition in favor of a new way of seeing things.” (&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gvsu.edu/cms4/asset/843249C9-B1E5-BD47-A25EDBC68363B726/from-safe-spaces-to-brave-spaces.pdf&quot;&gt;Robert Boostrom, quoted here&lt;/a&gt;.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent more than a year of sheltering in place, working from home full time, and leaving only for essential purposes. This year has presented me with opportunities and challenges that I’ve experienced but not reflected on in a larger context of their impact on me. The kick-off session reminded me that I could create space for this reflection.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="learning" /><category term="coaching" /><category term="questions" /><summary type="html">Wow, what a beginning.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Starting</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Starting" /><published>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</published><updated>2021-03-10T13:51:43-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/03/10/starting.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post is a test.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this post is a starting point for my work on Northwestern’s Organizational and Leadership Coaching Certificate. I’m pursuing it as part of a Master’s of Science in Learning and Organizational Change. That’s a mouthful, I know. I’ll add more detail in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Right now, I’m testing systems and building my own website to remind myself that this is a form of creative expression.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve pulled the bandaid off now, let’s see where we go.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="msloc" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">This post is a test.</summary></entry></feed>