<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-09-26T17:50:06-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">verbful</title><subtitle>Doing the work to make the idyl possible.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SMART v POSITIVE</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/smart-v-positive" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SMART v POSITIVE" /><published>2022-01-22T13:51:43-08:00</published><updated>2022-01-22T13:51:43-08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/smart-v-positive</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/smart-v-positive">&lt;p&gt;There are many approaches to making progress on goals and selecting an approach that feels appropriate can be a great first step on the path.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;💡&lt;em&gt;Something to consider:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Our current work culture in the USA frequently encourages us to always do more, work harder, and keep pushing. While there are times when pushing is the best next step, sometimes making a transformative change is more accessible when using a new approach that challenges our assumed ways of working.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;This might even include doing less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost everyone has encountered a SMART goal. From a &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;get shit done&lt;/code&gt; perspective, what’s not to like about a system that encourages us to set goals that are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Specific What will be accomplished? What actions will you take?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Measurable What data will measure the goal? (How much? How well?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Achievable Is the goal doable? Do you have the necessary skills and resources?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Relevant How does the goal align with broader goals? Why is the result important?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Time-Bound &lt;em&gt;**&lt;/em&gt;What is the time frame for accomplishing the goal?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But let’s get beyond SMART and think about frameworks that embrace us as humans in a specific context. By considering our motivations, experience, and context as we set a goal, we can increase our likelihood of succeeding &lt;em&gt;in the way that we want to succeed&lt;/em&gt; rather than being unsatisfied when we achieve the goal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An alternative that’s useful is POSITIVE, a model that draws on a cognitive behavioral therapy approach. POSITIVE’s granularity can help you review multiple factors that impact your ability to achieve your goals. Here are some examples of key questions in each step:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Purpose: What is it you want to achieve?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Observations: What have you tried so far?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Strategy: What does success look like for you?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Insight: How committed are you in achieving this goal on a scale of 1 – 10?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Team: Who will you share your goal with?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Initiate: When will you start to act on this?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Value: How will you celebrate your success?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Encourage: How are you going with your goals?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to SMART, POSITIVE immediately encourages you to think about more than just &lt;code class=&quot;language-plaintext highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;How will I execute on this goal?&lt;/code&gt; It also makes POSITIVE a useful tool to assess whether this goal should be continued or modified as you work towards completion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve used POSITIVE with a long-term project at several key moments:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;As I’m considering a project, I’ll use this framework to identify areas that require additional work before I start. For example, I might be clear on how I’ll measure success, but not sure who is available to team with me to reach the goal.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mid-way towards a goal, I like to review POSITIVE to see what’s changed. Do I have new information and observations that change my delivery timeline? Do I feel more or less certain that I’ll achieve this goal?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At the end, I lean into how I planned to celebrate the success. This helps me avoid situations where I’m so grateful to be done that I sweep difficult work under a carpet and forget about it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a deeper dive into more coaching models, consider reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Libri, V. (2004). Beyond GROW: In search of acronyms and coaching models. The International Journal of Mentoring and Coaching, 2(1), July. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.emccglobal.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/02/29-1.pdf&quot;&gt;Available here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">There are many approaches to making progress on goals and selecting an approach that feels appropriate can be a great first step on the path.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Smallest next step</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/09/15/2021-smallest-next-step.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Smallest next step" /><published>2021-09-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/09/15/2021-smallest-next-step</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/09/15/2021-smallest-next-step.html">&lt;p&gt;I woke up to realize that September is half over. There’s a lot to be grateful for: where I live, the weather is wonderful this time of year. There’s also plenty to worry about: &lt;em&gt;where has the year gone? how will I hit the upcoming deadline? what is causing this nervous pit in my stomach?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next week, I start the Fall Quarter of my coaching program (2 done! 2 to go!). While I love school, the looming deadlines, the exhaustion of learning and practicing new skills, and the ever-changing world sometimes feels like a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the run up to Day 1, I’ll be reminding myself to ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What is the smallest next step that I can take?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this moment, writing this post is my smallest next step to prepare for school.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">I woke up to realize that September is half over. There’s a lot to be grateful for: where I live, the weather is wonderful this time of year. There’s also plenty to worry about: where has the year gone? how will I hit the upcoming deadline? what is causing this nervous pit in my stomach?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching reflection aid</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/coaching-reflection-aid" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching reflection aid" /><published>2021-08-28T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-28T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/coaching-reflection-aid</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/coaching-reflection-aid">&lt;p&gt;After reflecting on clients, relationships, and how we can work together, I compiled this image to help set expectations and encourage me to push deeper. I like transforming information from 1 format to another. It gives my brain time to focus on different aspects of the topic at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/post-assets/coaching-reflection-aid.png&quot; alt=&quot;coaching-reflection-aid.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I look at this, I find myself thinking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This is only a snapshot in time of my coaching perspective. How will this table change over the coming months and years?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In what ways am I not pushing myself to go deeper and stretch further to be an even better coach?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What components have I forgotten to include? Should I add more content or reprioritize and focus?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">After reflecting on clients, relationships, and how we can work together, I compiled this image to help set expectations and encourage me to push deeper. I like transforming information from 1 format to another. It gives my brain time to focus on different aspects of the topic at hand.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Powerful questions as a tool to master</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/15/powerful-questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Powerful questions as a tool to master" /><published>2021-08-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/15/powerful-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/15/powerful-questions.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a curious person and love asking questions, but not all questions are equal. &lt;a href=&quot;https://positivepsychology.com/coaching-questions/&quot;&gt;This article&lt;/a&gt; describes powerful questions a tool that “ignites the imagination … and helps to overcome boundaries.” As a coach, I want to develop skills to ask even better questions for my clients so that they can find their own answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a coaching client, I struggle when I’m told  that “the answer is inside you the whole time.” Perhaps powerful questions can unlock those answers that actually ARE present for each client? Can I be an interlocutor to help people unlock their own personal truths?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If yes, how can I ask the right question at the right time to help people find answers?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to years of experimentation before I get anywhere close to mastery on asking powerful questions.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">I’m a curious person and love asking questions, but not all questions are equal. This article describes powerful questions a tool that “ignites the imagination … and helps to overcome boundaries.” As a coach, I want to develop skills to ask even better questions for my clients so that they can find their own answers.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Categories of question</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/09/categories-of-questions.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Categories of question" /><published>2021-08-09T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-09T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/09/categories-of-questions</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/2021/08/09/categories-of-questions.html">&lt;p&gt;I’m a curious person and I love a good question. This leads me to ponder questions in the back of my mind while running or to save good questions from other. In my next run, I’ll be thinking about this quote from the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.oreilly.com/library/view/humble-inquiry-second/9781523092642/&quot;&gt;2nd edition of Humble Inquiry&lt;/a&gt;, where Edgar Schein notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Keeping up with the content of accelerating change is really hard. … Yet trying to keep up with the content of accelerating change may actually be less important than keeping up with the context of accelerating change. There is a real difference between the content question “What changed?” and the context question “What is going on?” or “Why is this happening?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the next weeks, I’ll be asking:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do my questions in different arenas, relationships, and topics focus on context or content?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When does a context questions feel more natural?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What questions are impactful for particular clients?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">I’m a curious person and I love a good question. This leads me to ponder questions in the back of my mind while running or to save good questions from other. In my next run, I’ll be thinking about this quote from the 2nd edition of Humble Inquiry, where Edgar Schein notes:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">What is presence</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="What is presence" /><published>2021-08-04T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-04T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/micro-blog/2021/08/04/what-is-presence.html">&lt;p&gt;And how can I bring presence to the coaching experience?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presence is defined by the dictionary as: &lt;em&gt;“the state or fact of existing, occurring, or being present in a place or thing.”&lt;/em&gt; Alternatively the &lt;a href=&quot;https://coachingfederation.org/core-competencies&quot;&gt;International Coaching Federation&lt;/a&gt; defines presence as &lt;em&gt;“Ability to be fully conscious and create spontaneous relationship with the client, employing a style that is open, flexible and confident.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presence feels fully distinct from “being present” which is something that is done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My current thoughts are that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence is a shared experience that we can experience if we create the space and opportunity to connect&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence can be given by one person to another&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Presence creates the possibility to discover by allowing the unexpected to happen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><summary type="html">And how can I bring presence to the coaching experience?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trust building online</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/trust-building-online" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trust building online" /><published>2021-07-15T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-15T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/trusted-advisor-coaching</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/trust-building-online">&lt;p&gt;Trust is such an important foundation for working with anyone. The Trusted Advisor has a formula for trust that is &lt;a href=&quot;https://trustedadvisor.com/why-trust-matters/understanding-trust/understanding-the-trust-equation&quot;&gt;described in this video&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust = (Credibility, Reliability, and Intimacy) / Self-orientation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, trust is experienced as a physical experience of comfort and stability. This analytic model appeals to my brain, but misses the depth of experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure how I can use this forumla to be of service to clients - especially as we build relationships in this online world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My question about trust: How can I build trusting relationships with clients in a purely online world?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">Trust is such an important foundation for working with anyone. The Trusted Advisor has a formula for trust that is described in this video:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Boundaries and space</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/boundaries-and-space" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Boundaries and space" /><published>2021-07-07T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-07T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/boundaries</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/boundaries-and-space">&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking a lot about boundaries while going on long walks. Looking at sidewalks, single track paths, and steep ravines, the boundaries guided me from danger and helped me reach my destinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While boundaries can be seen as fences that block us from reaching our goals, what if boundaries create safe spaces for us to act in alignment with our needs and wants?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By creating boundaries, can I ask a coach create a space for my client to step in and own the resolution of a problem? Will this feel like withholding help or will it feel like holding space for the client to step in take up the space?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this area will be an essential topic to discuss with clients as we establish and continuously refine our work together.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">I’ve been thinking a lot about boundaries while going on long walks. Looking at sidewalks, single track paths, and steep ravines, the boundaries guided me from danger and helped me reach my destinations.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Considering resistance</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Considering resistance" /><published>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/general/micro-blog/2021/07/01/considering-resistance.html">&lt;p&gt;Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My most common form of resistance takes the form of continuously looking for more information. This often takes the form of:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;seeking more details&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;searching for the perfect solution&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;believing that resolution can be discovered through additional research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This perpetual hunt for details and information stops me from applying what I already know, which is often enough to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Resistance occurs from time to time during coaching as clients work towards goals. We can move through resistance together by recognizing it is happening, making a plan to engage with the resistance, and creating space for the client to address it with courage and without judgment.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="micro-blog" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="learning" /><summary type="html">Resistance is a natural reaction that insulates us from challenge and change. Sometimes resistance helps us persist through difficulty or protects us from risks. But it can outlive those difficulties and become a habit that reduces our ability to achieve goals. Resistance takes many forms and can play on our strengths, like curiosity, problem solving, and common sense, to make it safe to continue without changing our patterns.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Coaching with consulting models</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/coaching-with-consulting-models" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Coaching with consulting models" /><published>2021-06-30T14:51:43-07:00</published><updated>2021-06-30T14:51:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/process-consulting</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/coaching-with-consulting-models">&lt;p&gt;Edgar Schein describes 3 models of working with clients in his article “What is process consultation?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Process Consultation Model, coach and client will work together 50/50 from initial discovery and diagnosis. Instead of solving problems for the client, the process consultant teaches the client how to solve their own problems and supports them through the process. Schein notes that “expertise is less relevant than… the skills of involving the client in self-diagnosis and helping… find a remedy that fits his particular situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schein notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Process Consultation is the creation of a relationship with the client that &lt;em&gt;permits the client to perceive, understand, and act&lt;/em&gt; on the process events that occur in the client’s internal and external environment in order to improve the situation as defined by the client.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Expertise Model emphasizes specialized knowledge and applying highly technical skills to a client who has already appropriately diagnosed a problem (Schein, 1999, p 7). The expert model allows a consultant to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Show targeted specialization in a narrow, highly specific field&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Focus on providing a specific solution without participating in diagnosis&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Assess the outcome effectively for the client using their expertise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Doctor-Patient model envisions a role that assesses the situation to create a diagnosis which is shared with the patient/client to select the most appropriate treatment plan (Schein, 1999, p 11). The consultant may administer the prescribed response, but will certainly provide a highly detailed presentation of findings and recommendations to show their value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My questions are: How can I balance these different models to best support my clients? How will I get feedback about what is working or not? How can I continuously increase my skills across these models to be optimally effective?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;References:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schein, E. H. (1999). What is process consultation? Process consultation revisited: Building the helping relationship (pp. 3-29). Reading, PA: Addison-Wesley.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="general" /><category term="olcc" /><category term="micro-blog" /><summary type="html">Edgar Schein describes 3 models of working with clients in his article “What is process consultation?”</summary></entry></feed>